# Michael Cheng

626-731-0459 • michaelcheng022@gmail.com • github.com/michaelcheng022

## SUMMARY

Recent college graduate working as a junior software engineer specializing in front end development. Have taken computer science classes in college as well as bootcamp courses over the past two years. Strong background in customer and team relations. Currently seeking full-time opportunities as a Software Engineer to grow my skills as a front-end developer

#### SKILLS

- **Programming Languages**: JavaScript, HTML5, C++ (basic)
- **Technologies/Skills**: CSS3, Bootstrap, React.js, Redux, Node.js, MongoDB, npm/yarn, git, OOP, REST API, Git, ES6/7, GraphQL, Apollo, Yoga Server, Prisma, PHP

## EXPERIENCE

## **Junior Software Engineer**

AT6, LLC | Los Angeles, CA

Jan 2019 – Present

- Worked closely with designers to implement product features
- Build products for startups and enterprise organizations using React.js, Node.js and other JavaScript-related technologies.
- Created content-management system (CMS) for startup to manage their clients real-estate listings, using React.js, Next,js, Apollo Client, Yoga Server, GraphQL and Prisma

## **Junior Developer (Contract)**

Moving Analytics Inc. | Los Angeles, CA

March 2019 - June 2019

- Worked with VP of Product Design to push out new site features for company website
- Enabled ability for users to email through creation of contact form and email functionality using HTML and PHP
- Using Google reCAPTCHA API, reduced spam email accounts from 56% to 7%

## Personal Projects

## Wiki Viewer App

A search engine powered by Wikipedia - https://michaelcheng022.github.io/wiki-viewer-app/

- Search engine implements AJAX to retrieve Wikipedia API to produce search results
- Demonstrates knowledge of advanced DOM manipulation and functional programming

### YelpCamp

Basic Yelp Clone that allows users to upload/view campsites - https://yelp-camp-4422.herokuapp.com/

- Demonstrates knowledge of Object-Oriented Programming and modular programming
- Incorporates user authentication middleware using Passport.js
- Implemented backend NodeJS webbook and uses MongoDB hosted on Heroku
- Structured backend using REST API for route management

## **Hacker-News Client**

A hacker-news client fetching from HN Algolia search API - https://hn-algolia-clone.herokuapp.com/

- Single page application created using ReactJS w/ Redux
- Features search syntax highlighting, pagination, and mobile-compatibility
- Implements live search with caching, optimized for performance
- Combined with API caching and DOM manipulation, renders full time to interactive in 100ms

#### Web Portfolio

A personal portfolio website - https://michaelcheng022.github.io/portfolio/

- Created with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to create a minimalistic theme.
- Implemented CSS3 animations to make site fluid and dynamic
- Utilized the web design libraries jQuery and Bootstrap for responsive pages and mobile-compatibility.

#### EDUCATION

## University of California Riverside

BA, Economics Administrations w/ Information Systems Concentration

Sept 2014 – Dec 2018

Relevant coursework: Intro to Computer Science, Intro to Programming, Data Structures & Algorithms